GOKUL S





Gokul S

Cloud & DevSecops engineer





Cloud Sequrity

Summary

A Dedicated individual with strong focus & passion for Cloud and Cyber Security with more than 2.7 years of industrial experience in Fin-tech. Proficient in cloud architecture & security principles and practices, software development methods, project management and NIST Framework. Strong problem-solving skills and ability to work effectively in a team-based environment.

Professional Experience

Fidelity National Information Services (FIS)

DevSecOps Engineer

Dec 2021 - Aug 2023

- Administered containerized applications using Kubernetes platforms (Open Shift, GKE) for deployment, patching, and maintenance
- Maintained and monitored Production environment 24x7 using **Google Operation Suite & Dynatrace, Splunk** to analyze application data, performance and logs of the system following NIST Framework.
- Independently managed and renewed 1,000+ SSL certificates for 150+ Digital One Banks using **Venafi, Akamai,** and **Key factor.** Coordinated with the Client & other teams to install them.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to mitigate threats & incident establishing clear lines of communication between respective parties maintaining **CIA** Confidentiality, Integrity and Availability.
- Utilized **Service Now Snow** and **Jira** for incident, change, and user account management **(IAM & ACL)**. Effectively resolved application issues and provided solutions.
- Leveraged **Confluence**, **FIS-wiki**, **and One Note** to facilitate knowledge transfer. Created play books, conducted knowledge-sharing sessions, and documented processes.

IT Trainee Oct 2021 - Dec 202

- Generated project status and daily health check reports using Cloud Monitoring tools (**Thousand Eyes & Tryambak**) for upper management review.
- Identified and remediated security vulnerabilities through weekly system validations of Linux and Windows servers.
- Proficient in 8 Cyber Security Domains, NIST Frameworks, Terraform, Docker, and Agile & DevOps methodologies.
- Proactively monitored system performance using Grafana to identify potential performance bottlenecks and ensure optimal system up time.

DXC Technologies (HPE)

Associate Software Developer

Feb 2021 - Aug 2021

- Analyzed business data using to identify key trends and create data visualizations for informed decision making.
- Implemented software patches and deployed new versions to strengthen system security and prevent breaches.
- Delivered technical support to customers, troubleshooting and resolving their technical inquiries.
- Successfully identified and resolved technical issues by facilitating team meetings, escalating complex problems.

Skills

- Google Cloud Platform
- Cloud Flare
- Cyber Security
- Cloud Computing
- Computer Networking
- Linux
- Python & Bash
- Problem Solving
- Kubernetes
- Communication
- SQL
- Leadership
- Document control
- Al
- Analytical
- Project Management

Education & Certifications

- Google Professional Cyber Security May 2024
- Google Cloud Associate Engineer Feb 2024
- Google Cloud Digital Leader Nov 2023
- ISC2 Certified in Cyber Security Oct 2023
- Google Cloud Platform Boot camp Aug 2023 Oct 2023
- Cisco NDG Linux Unhatched course Jul 2023
- Bachelor of Computer Science and Engineering 2017-2021

Projects

- <u>Cloud Resume JSON API</u> Fire store, Cloud Function and Cloud Run (Python)
- Honey Pot in Cloud TPOT Framework, Elastic and Kibana
- Self-deployed website on GCP VM with Cloudflare CDN (HTML/CSS) & Gemini and Apache - <u>Cloud Sequrity</u>.